ANGELA DESLANDES - DATA ANALYST

NORWICH, CT | 213-712-4612 | ang.deslandes@amail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Data analyst and student of the Thinkful Data Analytics program. Developing proficiency with dashboarding, performance tracking, Pandas, Excel, SQL, Tableau, and Python to transform data into meaningful and easily understood visualizations and presentations. Gained experience in the US Navy to effectively utilize complex problem solving where relevant information was reviewed to develop and implement solutions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software: Microsoft Excel, Python, Tableau, SQL, PostgreSQL, Microsoft PowerPoint

Data Methods: Statistical analysis, data visualization, presentation design, data cleaning, data discovery, data exploration, data modeling, A/B testing

Additional Tools: Project management, business strategy, business intelligence, report generation

DATA ANALYSIS PROJECTS

Business Analysis - Revenue Growth Models - Lariat Rent-A-Car: | Thinkful | Link

05/2023

- Examined and cleaned historical sales data using Excel (VLookUp and pivot tables).
- Completed exploratory data analysis to identify strategic scenarios to increase revenue, assessed by KPI performance.
- Presented models that showcased a 20% increase in profits, while lowering or maintaining operational costs.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bally's Twin River Casino

Lincoln, RI

Surveillance Officer

07/2019 - 06/2022

- Reviewed security footage using Genetek and iTrak systems to report Daily Logs and notate incidents throughout the property.
- Conducted routine audits on employees spanning 114 live table games to ensure compliance with regulations and protocols.
- Analyzed visual information for over 4,200 slot machines and virtual table gaming machines with attention to detail to identify patterns and anomalies.

Palladion Services LLC

Boston, MA

Security Officer

09/2018 - 09/2019

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to provide insights based on surveillance data on three different properties.
- Prepared written reports of daily activities, observations, and incidents to ensure accurate documentation.
- Monitored CCTV security footage for suspicious activity, trespassers, and potential threats.

US Navy

NAS Lemoore, CA

Aviation Structural Mechanic, Safety Equipment

09/2012 - 09/2016

- Leveraged complex problem-solving skills to review relevant information and develop solutions on 12 F/A-18E/F Super Hornet naval aircraft.
- Identified the cause of operating errors and provided efficient troubleshooting while using pertinent data and individual judgment to ensure compliance with naval laws, regulations, and standards.
- Executed over 1,894 maintenance actions specializing in Environmental Control Systems, Life Support Systems, Egress / Ejection Seat maintenance, and basic corrosion control.

EDUCATION

Thinkful

Online

Certificate, Data Analytics

05/2023 - 08/2023

 Produced and presented professional projects and presentations from concept to completion focused on business forecasting, price modeling, and statistical analysis Developed skillsets in data analytics systems including Pandas, Excel, PostgreSQL, Tableau and Python, as well as methodologies including dashboarding, performance tracking, data wrangling, cleaning, and analysis

Coursera
Certificate, Google Data Analytics Professional

Online 12/2023

University of Rhode Island

Kingston, RI 12/2023

BA, Computer Science

• Relevant coursework: Statistical Analysis, Database Management, Data Visualization, Programming for Data Analysis